<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>KWmassage | Registered Massage Therapy in Kitchener/Waterloo</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 16:15:05 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 16:15:05 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Can Deep Tissue Massage Therapy Treat</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Deep tissue massage can treat man things, including:

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;ul class=&quot;blue&quot;&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Arthritis&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Back pain&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Carpal tunnel syndrome&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Chronic pain&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Compression syndromes&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Contractures&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Cramps&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Degenerative disc disease(DDD)&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Dislocations&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Dupuytrens&#39; contracture&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Fibrositis and fibrosis&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Foot/plantar fasciitis/ples planus - flat foot fractures&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Frozen shoulder&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Headache / migraine&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Herniated disc&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Iliotibial band contracture&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Jaw pain/TMJ&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Knee injury&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Low Back Pain&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Muscle spasms/ strain rehabilitation&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Neck pain/ torticollis&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Osteoarthritis/ rheumatoid arthritis&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Plantar fasciitis&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Postural disorders / scoliosis&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Pre / post-surgical and post-injury rehabilitation&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Relief of pain&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Repetitive strain injuries&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Scars&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Sciatica&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Sports injuries&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Sprains/strains / ligament and joint athletic injuries&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Stiff joints&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Tendonitis/ bursitis/neuritis&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Thoracic outlet syndrome&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Whiplash disorders WAD&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//generalmassagetherapy/what-can-deep-tissue-massage-treat/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//generalmassagetherapy/what-can-deep-tissue-massage-treat/</guid>
        
        
        <category>generalmassagetherapy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A New Way to Make a KW Massage Therapy Appointment</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am making another change to the way I do business. I have registered &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//&quot;&gt;KWMassage&lt;/a&gt; for a &lt;a title=&quot;Book with KW Massage Online&quot; href=&quot;https://kwmassage.cliniko.com/bookings#service&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CliniKo.com&lt;/a&gt; account. Cliniko will allow me to take appointments online, control my schedule, record clinical notes, write receipts for my services and do my bookkeeping all within the same software system. The only change you will notice is the online scheduler will look and operate a little different and hopefully you will get better service.

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now instead of using Schedulicity to make and change appointments on my website you will be using Cliniko. I will replace the schedulicity software widget on the KWmassage website with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//clinic-information&quot;&gt;Cliniko widget&lt;/a&gt; so you will still have access to my calendar from the same location on the KWmassage website. There are only a few differences between the two systems. First Cliniko does not require you to have and remember a user name and password. You will now have to enter you name, date of birth and contact info instead. Cliniko will then match you to an existing client account or create a new one for you. The only drawback to Cliniko is that it will not enable you to cancel appointments yourself; you will need to contact me via email, text or phone. In the event that you want to change an appointment, simple make the new appointment then message me to delete the old one. I recognize that this may be a small inconvenience to some but hopefully not having to remember a user name and password and the huge improvement in my usability will be enough to balance this out. You will continue to get email reminders of your massage appointments from Cliniko.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously I used Outlook for communications and contact management, QuickBooks for receipts and bookkeeping, Business contact manager for clinical notes and Schedulicity for calendar and online appointments. Having four different programs managing four different aspect of information for one client was very redundant and cumbersome. I was doing a lot of quadruple entry, not only was this time consuming but it also created space or errors in data input. As well it certainly was not encouraging to stay on top of my paperwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal is to allow Cliniko to help me be more efficient, more accurate, more detailed and timelier with your clinical notes. This will make it easier for me to stay up to date and informed with your health history and offer you better care.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2014 12:45:20 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//generalmassagetherapy/a-new-way-to-make-a-kw-massage-therapy-appointment/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//generalmassagetherapy/a-new-way-to-make-a-kw-massage-therapy-appointment/</guid>
        
        
        <category>generalmassagetherapy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Epsom Salt Bath </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Because of the high magnesium content, Epsom salts bath can be helpful any time you are suffering from&lt;a href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//generalmassagetherapy/what-can-deep-tissue-massage-treat&quot;&gt; muscle achiness or strain&lt;/a&gt;. Please set aside 40 minutes and run a full bath, the temperature of the water should be as hot as you can comfortably tolerate (though please do not exceed 40 degrees Celsius). Place the Epsom salt bath crystals into the water and spend at least 20 minutes soaking and relaxing. &lt;/br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;

Keeping your neck and shoulder in the water as much as possible will allow the salts to work directly on the problematic muscles. This is also a great time to enjoy a glass of cold water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a diagnosed heart condition or are over the age of 50, please moderate the water temperature and avoid submerging yourself in hot water above the heart. If you have any concerns about whether a hot Epsom salt bath will affect you adversely, please contact your family physician before using an Epsom salts bath.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 12:47:46 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//generalmassagetherapy/epsom-salt-bath/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//generalmassagetherapy/epsom-salt-bath/</guid>
        
        
        <category>generalmassagetherapy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Does the Weather Make our Muscles Stiff? </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s May 16th and the weather in the Kitchener, Waterloo has been miserable. We had a few weeks of warmish weather but now we are right back to cold and rainy. You might ask why a &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//&quot;&gt;massage therapist &lt;/a&gt;would care about the weather. It’s been good for business, that’s why I care. Our muscles get tight and stiff, old pains come back to the surface, and new ones come out. When this happens, we need to see our massage therapist.

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our body’s main mechanism to create or retain heat is to increase our metabolism (the amount of food energy we burn). Our body does this by contracting our muscles. Notice how your shoulders rise up to your ears when you walk outside on a cold day without your jacket. Your legs, back, neck, shoulders, and all the muscles in your body will do this. This increase in muscle tension will increase stress on your joints, pull your body out of alignment, and create muscle imbalances. With this added stress to your body, many symptoms like&lt;a href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//stretching/stretch-your-upper-trapezius-muscle&quot;&gt; neck pain&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//stretching/low-back-pain&quot;&gt;back pain&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//generalmassagetherapy/tension-headaches-3&quot;&gt;headaches&lt;/a&gt;, and muscle achiness surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing your massage therapist will help decrease this muscle tension and correct your muscle imbalances.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 12:44:24 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//generalmassagetherapy/the-weather-does-make-our-muscles-stiff/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//generalmassagetherapy/the-weather-does-make-our-muscles-stiff/</guid>
        
        
        <category>generalmassagetherapy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Massage Therapy Music </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m not the kind of &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//&quot;&gt;massage therapist&lt;/a&gt; that plays nature sounds, new age music, or any of the other typical spa-type music for &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//clinic-information/note-to-new-massage-therapy-clients&quot;&gt;my clients&lt;/a&gt; while I’m working. My primary goal as a massage therapist is not relaxation; relaxation is a side effect of my style of therapy and sometimes sleep does come for some of my less rested clients. I’m more concerned with your muscular dysfunction; I don’t feel I need to play music that’s going to put you to sleep. This doesn’t mean I play punk or heavy metal; you’re likely to hear anything from jazz and classical to folk or blues music.

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;90% of the time I play &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cbc.ca/radio2/&quot;&gt;CBC Radio 2&lt;/a&gt; in my massage therapy room. I’m in Kitchener Ontario so if you want to have a listen to what Radio 2 is playing now, check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cbc.ca/video/radio-popup.html#networkKey=cbc_radio_2&amp;amp;programKey=eastern&quot;&gt;eastern regional broadcast&lt;/a&gt;. Radio 2 plays a whole range of music; classical, opera, jazz, folk, country, hip hop, blues… the list goes on. Every hour, on the hour, there is 5 minutes of world news, but I find this to be a small price to pay compared to radio commercials every 10-15 minutes. And hey -- it forces me to stay up to date on world events!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a backup, for those times when the opera gets to be too much or the hip hop to loud for my client, I always have my MP3 player as a backup. I’ll often have music like: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5T3FXFnoTzE&quot;&gt;Nina Simone&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HCQDWjN22X0&quot;&gt;Nora Jones&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BWVnZAJaq4Q&quot;&gt;Jack Jonson&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=otJY2HvW3Bw&quot;&gt;Lenard Cohen&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lWdG8NoFXY0&quot;&gt;U2&lt;/a&gt; on hand.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 12:34:47 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//generalmassagetherapy/massage-therapy-music/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//generalmassagetherapy/massage-therapy-music/</guid>
        
        
        <category>generalmassagetherapy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Do You Charge An Initial Consultation Fee For Massage Therapy Appointments?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;No, I do not charge an initial consultation fee for &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//clinic-information&quot;&gt;massage therapy treatments&lt;/a&gt;. I have a simple one page &lt;a title=&quot;Massage Therapy Health History Form&quot; href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Health-History.pdf&quot;&gt;Health History form&lt;/a&gt; for you to fill out, I take 5 minutes or so to go over this form inorder to get a general idea of what I’m treating before we begin. After reviewing your needs, we get started right away, any other information I need I can ask &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//clinic-information&quot;&gt;while I’m treating you&lt;/a&gt;.

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/br953TUGKxs?rel=0&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 11:26:49 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//generalmassagetherapy/initial-consultation-fee/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//generalmassagetherapy/initial-consultation-fee/</guid>
        
        
        <category>generalmassagetherapy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Back Pain and How to Massage at Home </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been treating &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//stretching/low-back-pain&quot;&gt;back pain&lt;/a&gt; successfully since 2005. My first clients came to me because of back pain. Over the years, I have found that the overall outcome of &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//generalmassagetherapy/what-is-deep-tissue-massage&quot;&gt;massage therapy treatments &lt;/a&gt;for back pain has as much to do with the client as it does the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//about&quot;&gt;massage therapist&lt;/a&gt;. The more a client is willing to do on their own, the better their recovery will be. If a client is willing to do the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//stretching/general-guidelines-for-stretching&quot;&gt;stretches&lt;/a&gt;, exercises, and other home care recommended by their massage therapist, they get better sooner.

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;II often recommend stretching and strengthening exercises to enhance my massage therapy treatments. I also recommend &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//generalmassagetherapy/epsom-salt-bath&quot;&gt;hot and/or cold applications &lt;/a&gt;a lot, depending on the injury.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IOne thing I don’t talk much about in my &lt;a title=&quot;clinic&quot; href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//clinic-information&quot;&gt;clinic&lt;/a&gt; is how to massage at home. I assume that a client will come into see me as often as necessary until they have recovered, so it isn’t beneficial to take the time to teach them how to massage at home. However, sometimes a client can’t see me as often as they would like. Under these situations, it can be very helpful to learn the basics of how to massage yourself, or someone else, at home. You can apply this information to any part of the body. Today, I’m going to focus on back pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trick to a successful massage consists of 3 basic principles:
&lt;ol class=&quot;number&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;general – specific – general&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;superficial – deep – superficial&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;slowly warm and soften the tissue you want to work on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
Always follow these 3 principles when doing massage on yourself or anyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I massaging, never dive right in and start treating the injured tissue directly right away. It’s important to always start broadly (general) and lightly (superficial). Gently work the muscles and tissues around the injury first. Once the general area is starting to soften and warm up, you can SLOWLY work your way in towards the muscles you are trying to affect. Once you are working directly on an injured muscle, it’s important that you use slow, firm pressure along the length of the muscle. After about 2 minutes of direct work, or until you feel the muscle start to soften, it’s time to slowly start working your way back out to the superficial and general areas around the injury.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I Always start and end a massage treatment with gentle pressure. Never try to achieve the same pressure that a &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//generalmassagetherapy/governance-of-massage-therapy&quot;&gt;trained massage therapist &lt;/a&gt;uses, you are likely to hurt the person you are working on as well as yourself. It takes a lot of time to develop the strength and control to do &lt;a title=&quot;What is Deep Tissue Massage?&quot; href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//generalmassagetherapy/what-is-deep-tissue-massage&quot;&gt;deep tissue therapy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be helpful to talk to your massage therapist about the injury you want to treat at home. Often the &lt;a title=&quot;Trigger Points and Trigger Point Therapy&quot; href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//generalmassagetherapy/trigger-points-and-trigger-point-therapy&quot;&gt;pain is coming from a different part of the body than you might think&lt;/a&gt;, and having a professional massage therapist help you locate the right area to work on can be helpful. He/she can also guide you with technique, anatomy, and help you confirm that there aren’t any contraindications for the style of massage you want to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When working on yourself, it can be hard to reach your back. Start with a hot pack to soften and relax the muscles. Then, there are a number of ways to reach those sore and hard-to-reach areas:
&lt;ul class=&quot;blue&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;lean into the corner of a wall using the edge on the muscle on either side of the spine&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;lie on a rolled towel and move around until you reach the right area&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;lie on a tennis ball on the floor to massage your own back&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Massaging yourself, a friend, or a loved one can be a great way to help relieve back pain. Always make sure you have a clear idea of what you want to achieve and if you’re not sure, consult with a professional.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 11:21:56 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//generalmassagetherapy/back-pain-and-how-to-massage-at-home/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//generalmassagetherapy/back-pain-and-how-to-massage-at-home/</guid>
        
        
        <category>generalmassagetherapy</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kitchener Massage Therapist makes another Rock Climbing Trip </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This Saturday my family and I are leaving for a &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//about/rock-climbing-as-a-lifestyle/&quot;&gt;rock climbing &lt;/a&gt;trip and vacation. We are leaving &lt;a title=&quot;KWmassage Clinic Location&quot; href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//contact&quot;&gt;Kitchener Waterloo&lt;/a&gt;, on March 10, 2012. I will be returning to work March 22&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt;, 2012. If you are looking for a &lt;a title=&quot;Massage Therapy Appointment in Kitchener Waterloo&quot; href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//clinic-information&quot;&gt;massage therapy appointment&lt;/a&gt; I will be available before and after this trip.

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for a massage therapy appointment unfortunately I have very little time left before I leave, Wednesday March 7&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; is the only option. The week I get back will be a short one but I still have a little time on the 22&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; to &lt;a title=&quot;Book a massage therapy appointment in Kitchener Waterloo&quot; href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//clinic-information&quot;&gt;book appointments&lt;/a&gt;. The following week, March 26&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, is starting to booking up already but I still have a sometime most days that week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will be flying into Las Vegas and staying right on the strip for 3 days. After this we will drive down to Joshua Tree (JT), California, were we have a small bungalow rented for a week. While in Vegas, we will make a few trips out to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mountainproject.com/v/red-rock/105731932&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Red Rock Canyon&lt;/a&gt; to do some climbing. We will have the kids so our objectives will be limited but we will still do some great climbs. The first climbing day we will do Panty Wall in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mountainproject.com/v/calico-basin/105731977&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Calico Basin&lt;/a&gt; where my wife is looking forward to practicing her leading skills (single pitch sport climbing, 5.7-5.11). Depending on how things go the first day we would like to do &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mountainproject.com/v/physical-graffiti/105732266&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Physical Graffiti&lt;/a&gt; (two pitch trad climb, 5.6) the second day. Our bungalow in JT is only 15 minutes from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mountainproject.com/v/joshua-tree-national-park/105720495&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Joshua Tree National Park&lt;/a&gt;, a world famous climbing area with over 8000 thousand route. I hope to get in 4 or 5 climbing and exploring days while in there. I don’t have the JT guide book yet (I will pick it up at &lt;a href=&quot;http://desertrocksportslv.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Desert Rock Sports in Las Vegas&lt;/a&gt;) so I haven’t planned our climbing objectives. I will write a trip report when we get back with more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I apologize to anyone hoping to make a massage therapy appointment while I’m gone. I have tried to make up for the deficit by working a few extra evenings before and after the trip and even a Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 11:19:09 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//rock_climbing/kitchener-massage-therapist-makes-another-rock-climbing-trip/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//rock_climbing/kitchener-massage-therapist-makes-another-rock-climbing-trip/</guid>
        
        
        <category>rock_climbing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stretch Your Levator Scapula </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Levator Scapula muscle runs from the top tip of the shoulder blade up to the top four joints of the neck.  The Levator Scapula muscle lifts the shoulder blade and helps control side-to-side movement of the head. A &lt;a title=&quot;Trigger Points and Trigger Point Therapy&quot; href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//generalmassagetherapy/trigger-points-and-trigger-point-therapy&quot;&gt;Trigger Point&lt;/a&gt; in the Levator Scapula muscle can cause pain behind the head and to the back of the neck.

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To stretch your &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//generalmassagetherapy/tension-headaches-3&quot;&gt;Levator Scapula &lt;/a&gt;muscle, begin in a seated position. &lt;img class=&quot;imgbox&quot; alt=&quot;levator stretch pic&quot; src=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//wp-content/uploads/2014/01/levator-stretch-pic.jpg&quot; width=&quot;191&quot; height=&quot;120&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With your shoulders relaxed and your head in a natural position, carefully tuck your chin towards your right armpit. If more pressure is needed to feel the stretch, you can use your right hand to gently pull from the top of your head toward the right armpit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be sure not to allow your left shoulder to rise, as this will prevent the muscle from lengthening in to a stretched position. Repeat on the other side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be sure to review to my &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//stretching/general-guidelines-for-stretching&quot;&gt;General Guidelines for stretching &lt;/a&gt;before doing any of the stretches I demonstrate and recommend. It’s always a good idea to see a &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//generalmassagetherapy/governance-of-massage-therapy&quot;&gt;health care professional &lt;/a&gt;before starting a new exercise program.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 11:15:24 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//stretching/stretch-your-levator-scapula-2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//stretching/stretch-your-levator-scapula-2/</guid>
        
        
        <category>stretching</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Stretch Psoas Muscle </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Psoas muscle is a strong muscle at the front of your hip. It often affects your &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//generalmassagetherapy/back-pain-and-how-to-massage-at-home&quot;&gt;low back&lt;/a&gt; and an cause pain. If you sit for long periods of time, be sure to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JtnQHieEkqQ&quot;&gt;stretch the Psoas muscle &lt;/a&gt;often. &lt;/br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;Be sure to review to my &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//stretching/general-guidelines-for-stretching&quot;&gt;General Guidelines for stretching &lt;/a&gt;before doing any of the stretches I demonstrate or recommend. It’s always a good idea to see a &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//generalmassagetherapy/governance-of-massage-therapy&quot;&gt;health care professional&lt;/a&gt; before starting a new exercise program.

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/JtnQHieEkqQ?rel=0&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2014 11:10:11 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//stretching/how-to-stretch-psoase-muscle/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jeremykw.github.io/kwmassage-stage//stretching/how-to-stretch-psoase-muscle/</guid>
        
        
        <category>stretching</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
